Alf Bae

Founder of Forethink

alfpooh@gmail.com

Summary

I am making a pleasant user experience. I can lead all design process from front-end to final: concepting, drawing scenarios, building prototype, producing interaction design, and UX debugging in a lean way or traditional way.

I am a user experience designer with strong product building experience in designing successful products for consumer electronics & mobile phone. Especially, expert in innovative user experience concepting, building elegant user interface, and creative design directing.

Also, academic design research is the other pillar of my design career. I am a doctor in advanced design study, focusing on a service design for a society.

However, for users, I am just a humble listener and curious researcher who is trying to understand their deeper needs and real wants.

Specialties: Specialized in advanced user experience concepting, User interaction design for mobile device and IOT device. Designed courses for design students and often lead a workshop as a leader for creative innovation using UX methods such as Lego Serious Play, Informance (Informative performance, Bodystorming). Personally, life long Star Trek fan.

Experience

Founder

January 2016 - Present

Digital service startup. Building Vaikutin, an internet advertising solution. Produced iOS apps. (Fiksu Count, Fiksu Calc, Just Browse for Netflix)

Principal Designer at Microsoft

April 2014 - October 2015 (1 year 7 months)

- . Senior user experience designer for mobile phone accessory in Phone UX design
- . Developing IOT hub application, "Microsoft gadget" UI, in a LEAN way
- . Developing BTLE IOT Sensor, "Microsoft Treasure Tag" device UI and app. UI
- . Developing Screen Sharing, Miracast mirroring device: Device UX design

- . Developing Gear16 concept design: Ideation, UX scenario, planning for 2016 Gear UX
- . Developing Stereo BT headset: Device UX design
- # As IOT UX expert. Lead UX design from front-end (prototyping, UX workshop) to the end (specs and fit & finish).
- # My products in the market

UX Designer at Nokia

January 2013 - April 2014 (1 year 4 months)

• Senior user experience designer, Espoo, Finland

- Jan. 2013 Apr. 2014
- . Windows Mobile Phone application design, IOT Sensor related
- . Developing activity tracking app. Motion monitor for user's health, wellness, UX design
- . Developing Joyn RCS chat app. UX design

UX designer at Nokia

January 2013 - April 2014 (1 year 4 months)

• Principal user experience designer, Ulm, Germany

- June 2012 Dec. 2012
- . For Meego based platform, developing advanced concept designs
- # Design innovation in small screen UX such as QWERTY keypad for smallest smart phone, and natural behaviour with backside touch.

Principal designer at Nokia

April 2011 - May 2012 (1 year 2 months)

• Principal innovation expert, Beijing, China

April. 2011 – June 2012

- . Product innovation, Feature Phone division
- . Developing prototypes, innovative demonstrators for future Nokia products as chief designer
- # Lead innovation experts in UX innovation of Nokia S30/S40 platform. Low cost smart phone UX for B2B; solving daily productivity problems.

Principal partner

June 2010 - December 2010 (7 months)

- Principal Director
- . A founder and leader of user experience design consulting team
- . A family company of InnoDesign, a total design brand design studio since 1986

- . Chief designer director, consulting project for KT app store, web design for Korea Telecom (2nd largest mobile carrier in Korea)
- # My second start-up. UX team building and consulting for clients. Hoped to be a leading front-end UX consultancy for corporates.

Design Consultant at Philips

August 2008 - July 2009 (1 year)

Interaction Design Team

Royal Philips Design Consulting LTD. Hong Kong Branch

- . Managing and creating interaction design proposal, user interface guide and UI flow.
- . Touch UI for Google Android based mobile multimedia player, "GoGear Connect"
- . Touch & touch frame UI for digital photo frame
- . Touch based Human-Machine Interface for In Car Entertainment system, CED750, CID2680
- . Implementing Philips Brand Identity Design Architecture

User Experience Design at Motorola

April 2001 - July 2008 (7 years 4 months)

• Senior Design Researcher

Human Factors & Design Research Team Feb. 2006 – July 2008

- . Planning, executing, analyzing, and promoting global design research projects
- . Managing the Perceived Quality Control on product design, user interface design & engineering
- . Leader of research projects for touch interface principle study
- . Researching and designing language predictive input system for Korean, Chinese and Hinglish
- Lead Designer

User Interface Design Team Apr. 2004 – Feb. 2006

- . Managing UI/GUI design team for Sprint US
- . Producing user interface design guidelines and UI flow schematics
- . Designing innovative UI experience for advanced concepts and portfolio products
- Design Strategy Planner

Global Design Planning Team Apr. 2001 – Apr. 2004

- . Managing Global Trend Monitoring Program and published monthly newsletter
- . Researching ethnography researches and trend researches

- . Developing user experience design strategy, concept and process
- . Developing advanced product design concept for future Motorola business

Industrial Design at LG Electronics

December 1995 - March 1998 (2 years 4 months)

Research & Simulation Design Team., Corporate Design Center Information product design group.

- . Designing advanced digital products: design research, concept, and design
- PDA, DVD, Network Computer, Ergonomics keyboard.

Education

Hongik University

Doctor in advanced design study, Advanced design study, 2008 - 2015

Activities and Societies: IDAS (International Design Advanced Studying) Graduated at 2015

Hongik University

MFA, Industrial Design, 1998 - 2000

Activities and Societies: Amateure radio, HL0AEO

Hongik University

BFA, Industrial Design, 1990 - 1995

Activities and Societies: Industrial Design Dept.

Alf Bae

Founder of Forethink

alfpooh@gmail.com



Contact Alf on LinkedIn